<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<interview>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    Through <building xml:id="Building_1"> Ace Morgan </building>, He probably knew the building best, I think, because he was in every nook and 
cranny, hanging lights, doing things that were above my pay grade and knowledge and understanding. 
And he just really knew the building intimately. I mean the <building xml:id="Building_1"> building </building>. 
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    No, I'm familiar with that kind of person. We have people who now know the <place xml:id="Building_4">Eisner Center</place> back of their 
hands. 
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    Right,
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Right. But alright, I think it's recording now. And so for this, because it's an audio thing and because I 
would like people to know who we're talking about, could you just state for the audio your name in your 
class at here and what you studied at <institution xml:id="Institution_1"> Denison </institution>?
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    Sure. My name is <persName xml:id="Person_200"> Barbara </persName>, Bruce was my maiden name. My married name is Williams, <persName xml:id="Person_200">Barbara Bruce 
Williams</persName>. And I graduated from Denison as a theater arts major in 1970, having started in the fall of 1966. 
So those four years.
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Amazing. Okay. So now what I'm going to do for just for sharing purposes, I'm going to share my screen 
so you can see what I'm looking at. But essentially if it will, let me, please let me, oh, come on. Come on. 
Oh goodness. I'm not the best with Zoom. I should be way better at it by now.
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    No worries. Don't worry about it. Take the pressure off yourself.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    There is that button. There. Oh, it's right there. It's a big one. Okay, so can you now see a blueprint?
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    I can. I can.
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Okay. So I have three separate scans. This is what I have from the archives. This is the design plans of the 
    <building xml:id="Building_1"> building </building>. So I know there might be some differences, but this I believe is the <floor xml:id="Floor_0">basement floor</floor>. I have just 
    for you to see, we have the <floor xml:id="Floor_2">first floor</floor> here and as well as the <floor xml:id="Floor_1">ground floor</floor>, so that should be in a different 
    order. I'll start on the <floor xml:id="Floor_1">ground floor</floor>. Feel free to ask me to switch between any of these. But my main 
    question, my first couple of questions is, how much time did you spend in the <building xml:id="Building_1"> Theatre Arts Building </building> as 
when you were a student, and what were the kind of things that you were getting up to while you were 
there?
  </interviewer>
 <snippet n="1">
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    Yeah, let me talk about the non-rehearsal, non-performance use of the <building xml:id="Building_1"> building </building> first. Does that make 
sense?
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Yeah.
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    I don't remember. I probably declared as a theater major maybe sophomore year, but I took an 
    <class xml:id="Class_1">introduction to theater course</class> my freshman year. <persName xml:id="Person_160">Bill Brasmer</persName>, who was then the chair of the <program xml:id="program_1">theater 
      department</program>, taught that class. Some kids in that class, some students in that class stayed with <program xml:id="program_6">the major</program>
    and some didn't. And so that class was taught in the <room xml:id="Room_2">upstairs room</room> that was near the <entrance xml:id="Entrance_1">entrance</entrance>, the front 
    entrance to the <building xml:id="Building_1"> building </building>, near to where the <room xml:id="Room_3">box office</room> was.
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Was it called the <room xml:id="Room_2">library</room> by chance?
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    -Yes, that was exactly correct. It was wood lined as much of the interior of the <building xml:id="Building_1"> building </building> was, and the front 
    windows faced out to what was then <quad xml:id="Quad_2">sorority circle</quad>, which is where the <building xml:id="Building_5">cinema building</building> is now. Right. 
And I don't know, there were maybe 10 or 11 of us in that class. And then over the years when I then had 
already had by that time come into the <program xml:id="program_1">department</program> as a <program xml:id="program_6">major</program>, gosh, we used every corner of the <building xml:id="Building_1"> building </building> 
    pretty much as a classroom. There weren't a lot of classrooms in the <building xml:id="Building_1"> building </building>, so we just would set up and 
    find a place. And oftentimes it was in what we called <place xml:id="section_1">the pit</place>, which is where the audience would normally 
    sit when the shows were on the <place xml:id="section_2">main stage</place>. So we'd have classes there. We'd have classes down in the 
    <room xml:id="Room_4">green room</room>, especially acting classes every once in a while we'd use a room in a different building 
    question mark. So that was kind of the classroom use of the <building xml:id="Building_1"> building </building> as I remember it. Does that give you 
what you need?
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Yeah. So yeah, it's interesting to think about. Yeah, so I have these scans, and I know talking to <persName xml:id="Person_201">Mark 
Bryan</persName> a bit, he says some of the labels on here are kind of funny given that they weren't really used for 
    what they're describing. So the <room xml:id="Room_3">coat room</room> is where you guys had your <room xml:id="Room_3">box office</room>. I remember hearing 
about that. It had that little window near the entrance. But yeah, he talked a lot about how square footage 
you guys really got creative with how that <building xml:id="Building_1"> building </building> was used, especially for classrooms.
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    That's very true. And I'll get to the performance aspect of that in a little bit to the different stages and so 
forth.
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Yeah. So you say you used some of the <room xml:id="Room_4">green room</room> and the <room xml:id="Room_2">library</room> ?
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    There was another <room xml:id="Room_5">room</room> that was on the other side of the <room xml:id="Room_3">box office</room> facing the orientation of where the 
    <place xml:id="Building_4">Eisner building</place> is now. And that was also used for classroom space. It was very similar in size to the 
    <room xml:id="Room_2">library</room> , but it was a different room. I remember auditioning for a play in there for <persName xml:id="Person_160">Brasmer</persName> at one time. It's 
where he held a tryout.
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    You said it was similar size of the <room xml:id="Room_2">library</room>. Do you think it was, if I'm looking here on the screen, the 
    <room xml:id="Room_5">reception room</room>  here next to something called <place xml:id="Room_6" type="Room"> The Kitchen 
    </place>. Was it by a <stairwell xml:id="stairwell_1">stairwell?</stairwell>
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    Yes.
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Yeah. Okay. So he hosted an audition there. Do you remember what show that was for?
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    Yes, I do. Oh, isn't that awful? I'm not coming up with it. I'll send that to you.
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Yeah, I'm just curious now that you've mentioned him.
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    He actually finally, it was a two person cast and he did two casts. So he gave four actors the opportunity 
to act in it. It was the love story between, it was an Arnold Wesker play, see the Machine Works. And it 
was a romantic, a story about a romance of two people falling in love and then why it didn't work out. So 
I don't remember the name but it was an Arnold Wesker play.
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
    Did you end up doing that show?
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
    I did not. I was a junior at the time. He cast four seniors. He cast Mimi Beck with a fellow named Doug 
    Conditt- 
  </interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">
Conditt? Oh-
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">
-and he asked Lynn something with John. Lathrop. One thing that you should sort of maybe put aside for yourself is getting hold of as many copies of 
playbills as you might be able to find. I think they may have them, maybe not complete, up in the archives at the library up on the campus. And I have a collection of them too, from my four years if there's any 
gaps.
  </interviewee>
 </snippet>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah, that'd be great. I might be following up with you to fact check some things. This is a little bit of a 
stretch. I know last names are common. Do you know if Doug Condit was related to anyone who went to 
Denison before?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">I don't. I don't.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Okay. There was-</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">-And I don't know, did you see the email that I sent to your department chief and to Julie?</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah, it was a lovely email. Again, I haven't responded to yet, unfortunately, but I hope to</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">That's okay. And they haven't either. And I just have a feeling that everybody's busy and taking a break 
and everything. But Doug Conditt, I don't know if the alumni office can find him, and there are others too 
that really were very, very active and very important in the department. So anyway, we'll get to that later,</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Later. Absolutely.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Let stick with the building.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yes. Okay. I'm curious. You're talking about some of the classes you're telling me about, little bit about 
performance. Were there spots in the building? I know it was, again, you're being very economical with 
space, that students found themselves hanging out in or debriefing after class, rehearsal hangout spots. Do 
you remember any spots in the building that students gravitated towards?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Not really. I mean, if you were rehearsing in an area like down in the green room, sometimes you'd go 
down to the green room and you'd do sub-scenes down in the green room while the main stage was being 
used for the larger ensemble, if you understand what I'm saying. Is that clear? Okay. So there'd be 
breakout spaces and people would find different rooms to be in. I don't have a sense, having just had an 
oblique understanding of how the Eisner building is used, we didn't really go downhill to log a lot of time 
in the building when we were not needed in the building. That's my sense of it. And part of it was the 
logistics of uphill classes and downhill classes.
And one of the ways I think I learned to be a good planner in my life was planning my academic 
schedule. So you had to do those stairs as few times a day you could get away with.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah,</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Seriously.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah. That's smart. I've never mastered that because I'm always finding myself going up and down that 
hill way more times than I want to be in a day.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">I know. And I have to tell you, my legs have never been in such good shape in my entire life as my four 
years there. Honest to God,</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">I'll miss the days that my calves were this muscled.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">I know, I know. But to go back to the serious subject, that being said, if you had an hour between and you 
didn't have to be back uphill. If you had your books with you, you just found a place in the area next to 
the main auditorium, and I forget what that was called on
(12:34):
The first floor,
(12:36):
And you'd just study. But there wasn't a lot of comradery around it the way I sensed in the Eisner 
building, because you all had different academic schedules, and so it wasn't really a place to come and 
hang out. There weren't that many resources. There were no Coca-Cola machines and there were no snack 
machines and there wasn't the interdisciplinary of different arts down there anyway. You were more down 
there when you were working on a show, whether it was working on costumes or working on sets or 
actual rehearsals or, you know what I'm saying?</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah. Did you find yourself as a student, you said, I see you have a really extensive performing and 
directing history at Denison. Did you do things like costumes or sets? Did you ever find yourself doing 
technical</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Work? Oh, absolutely. We all did. Everything.
(13:41):
And I am very, very thankful for that. I mean, I didn't do lights. I mean, that would've been an insurance 
issue. University Tom did lights, but the rest of us, you were always being pressed into service in some 
way. If you weren't in a show, yes, you were being pressed into service. If you were in a show, you were 
being pressed into service. It didn't matter if you had the lead or not.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">We</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Were a small group of students. And so everybody's availability and however they could put their 
shoulder to the wheel was needed. And there was one show that I had the lead in a flea in her ear, which 
Elliot Stout directed. It was a French far farce by Fado. And the woman who was really the costume 
designer while we were there, she was a student, Lynn means, and she allowed me as the actress to come 
with her, choose the fabrics for my two costumes, and then work on them. And that gave me a 
tremendous boost up as an actress playing the role and wearing period costumes. It did. It was invaluable 
to me. And I would work on other shows too, as well, on costumes and miscellaneous stuff. They didn't 
let me into the shop too much to do the sawing and the hammering, but other female students did do that. 
It just wasn't my forte and not my nor interest to be candid.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Where in the building were you doing costumes the most? Was there a designated spot for that?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">There was no separate costume shop. Lynn was just a magician. I don't know how she ever did what she 
did upstairs in the building. There was the women's dressing room. The men's dressing room was a small 
one. It was right off the main stage. But the women's was upstairs, and that is where Lynn worked on the 
costumes. And she was always pulling out her sewing machine and setting it up. And she didn't have the 
luxury of what there is at the Eisner building. There may have been a permanent collection of costumes, 
and that may have been downstairs next to the Green Room. Tom may know more than I am 
remembering on that. So there was a collection of costumes from which Lynn could draw either to use as 
they were or to modify, or if they were really kind of tatty, just to try and salvage the material as best she 
could.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Right. Yeah. I mean, that's impressive that she could just operate where she could. Yeah, she was 
unbelievable costume people, I find to be some of the most ingenious, thrifty people</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">I know.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">That's incredible.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">And she let me make my hat that I wore as Ramon, the Kemetic lead in Flea. And again, that was such a 
gift to me as an actress, to have put the hat with feathers and everything together, and then I a greater 
sense of how to wear it and use it.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 6 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.
That's really cool to have that comfortability with your costume.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">It was really cool. And when she took me over to Newark to pick out the fabrics, and one of the fabrics 
that we picked out was a brown chiffon. It had white polka dots on it. It sounds tacky, but it was really 
cool. And she made that into a ruffle at the bottom of the skirt while having held the fabric in my hand 
and realizing the lightweight of chiffon, it gave me the idea, I'm going to make that skirt rustle and dance. 
And I taught myself to do that. And if I hadn't had the experience of understanding what the fabric could 
do that I did, never would've come to me.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Wow. No, that's incredible.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">It was very impactful. Those were, when we finished dress rehearsal, Elliot, who was very sparse in his 
patting you on the back, he cried out. He screamed out at me, Bruce, that was the maiden name. He called 
everybody by their last name. Bruce, how did you make that skirt dance? It was a moment for me. It was 
really a moment for me though.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Wow. No, that's incredible. Yeah. So you all had to be pretty resourceful and really help out in every 
other aspect. So you said there was a small group of students, so how close did you all get or were there 
factions? Friend groups are normal, but</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">No, we were very close. I would say we were very, very close. Three of us were roommates, Barbara 
Moan, Carolyn Clay, and me and Tom. I only remember the four of us as theater majors that graduated in 
'70. Somebody would have to check the records on that. And Tom verified my recollection, that was his 
too. But I'd want to check the records on that. And then there were uphill kids who had uphill majors in 
the English or history or one of the sciences or whatever, who came down show after show after show. 
And they were adjuncts. And we were close with a lot of those guys too. When we did &quot;Three Sisters&quot; 
and we had to stay over Thanksgiving vacation to do the final rehearsals for an early December opening. 
And we all got together and made a collaborative dinner, Thanksgiving dinner for the whole cast and 
crew that was at somebody's house. We could barely fit the table in. We had to so many people. And I 
made a dish that was an or it was called Shrimp Chekhov. So there was a lot of comradery. Of course, if 
you've got actors and actresses vying for roles, there's a competitiveness too. But that never, to my 
knowledge, interfered with the friendships and the collaboration. You'd talk it through. It was
(21:13):
A small
(21:13):
Department. You weren't going to bite your nose to spite your face.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah. Don't burn bridges in a group that small. No. Interesting. But</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 7 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.
Back to the building here.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yes. I mean, this is all relevant to me, so don't worry about sticking to the building.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Okay,</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Good.
(21:34):
It's the grounding point for good stories like this, so thank you. But yeah, so looking at some of my 
questions, so yeah, it was mostly a place to go work. You weren't necessarily going there to hang out, so 
you spent a lot of time in rehearsals. And so you said that was mostly in the arena space or in the pit 
space. Can you tell me, are there any rehearsal stories that stick out to you? Any, I don't know, long 
nights or something that you did in that space?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Well, I remember if you had a main stage show and the main stage wasn't being used for something else, I 
mean, you'd rehearse on the main stage. Sometimes what would happen is a show would be deliberately 
put into the pit. So for instance, Paul Hoffman directed a play our senior year called A Dream Play by 
August Sternberg. And it was a very, for its time, a very avant guard production. And he put that down in 
the pit, and the audience sat on the main stage and on the two side stages. So
(22:52):
The performing area was surrounded on three sides by audience, which was really cool for the actors. It 
was a very different experience for the actors. It was interesting. I don't ever remember a main stage 
production being on either of the two side stages. They really weren't big enough. They really just weren't 
big enough. But we used them a lot for rehearsing space and also for in-class improvs and in-class scene 
work that we didn't use the green room for. So that whole stage area was used a lot, even during the days 
when we were not performing. Does that make sense?</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yes, that does. So yeah, just being, again, using it for a number of different things. I love the idea of 
performing with the audience around you like that. The black box space that we still use, we definitely get 
a play around with where the audience gets to sit. And I've seen students get really creative with where 
they want their audiences. And you said that was directed by who again? Was that a student or was that a 
faculty member?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">That was Paul Hoffman, and he was a faculty member. My freshman year. Brasmer was the director of 
the department, and he hired, and they started our freshman year, three new faculty members.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Oh, wow.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 8 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.
One was Dr. Stout, Elliot Stout, who went on to start the cinema department.
(24:48):
Another was Paul Hoffman, and he was a tech guy, and he was really in charge of building and creating 
and designing the sets and the lighting and everything that went into it. Now, as Tom grew over his four 
years, he took a lot of the lighting off of Paul's shoulders and did the design work as well as just the 
mechanical work. But that was Paul's area. And then there was a female faculty member, Pam, isn't that 
awful? I'm blocking on her name. Pam Michaels. And her interest was kind of like reader's theater, 
elocution, voice, but she also did, she taught academic classes as well. You'd have to go back and look at 
the records as to what her assignments were. And she and Paul fell in love with each other. And by our 
senior, I think our senior year, they got married. They may have gotten married between our, over the 
summer, between junior and senior year, but you may find her under the name Pamela Hoffman.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Got it. That's good to know. So there's always been some kind of married couple in the department. Mark 
and Eleni being married was a revelation to me freshman year. That was a very fun one. That's awesome. 
That's great. Sorry,</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">I understand. But going back to using the pit as a
(26:26):
Performing area, when I was there, and I don't know if this is still true, but part of the graduation 
requirement was you had to do a practicum and whether it was a set design or a costume or something 
else, and I decided to direct a play, and I directed &quot;a Day in the Death of Joe Egg&quot; by Peter Nichols, 
which is a black comedy. And Carolyn Clay directed a Tom Stoppard play called &quot;The Real Inspector 
Hound&quot;. And both of those sets were built in the pit and the performances were in the pit. And again, you 
could have the audience three sides around. I think in part we did that because I had acted in a dream 
play, which was earlier that year, and had loved the experience of the audience on three sides. So when it 
came to doing &quot;Joe Egg,&quot; it was like, man, that's what I want for my play. That's
(27:48):
What I,
(27:52):
Needless to say, both shows showed in tandem. So one night it would be Carolyn's play, the Stoppard, 
and then it would be &quot;Joe Egg&quot;-. So the sets had to be very easily converted from one show to another, 
and they were,</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">What did the three side audience do for you? What was something that was exciting about it that made 
you want to choose that?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Well, you're gravitating to three sides instead of just a flat surface in front of you. And it made me, maybe 
it was just the avant-garde production that Paul did. I was the lead. I was the daughter of Indra, and I was 
dressed in a leotard and tights. Now that doesn't sound very avant-garde now, but it was then, and people 
wore masks, the actors wore masks to portray being a judge or to be portraying a different kind of role, a 
minister sort of taking out of the Commedia dell'arte tradition and modernizing that. But to go back to 
your question, just to have to rotate and keep in mind three different elevations that you had to make sure 
AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 9 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.
you paid attention to, it gave you a certain constant being on your toes and awareness. That was 
heightened for me.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah, no, I mean, I think that challenge,</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">And I think my sense was it gave the audience more, this is the thing that I wanted as a director. It gave 
the audience more of a sense of intimacy with the people acting on stage. They weren't up there higher 
than your head level. They were all around you and &quot;Joe Egg,&quot; It's a very intimate show. It's a very 
emotional show, and I really wanted that for my actors and for the audience.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah. Yeah. No, I think it's really incredible when you get to play with how sharing space with your 
audience and not making it just that proscenium experience-</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Exactly.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">-is vulnerable, but so exciting. That's a really, really fun thing to do. But yeah, being on the back foot, that 
definitely sounds familiar. Okay, I'm going to plug in my laptop. I realize it's about to die, and that's not 
very professional.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">I have to remind myself to do that all the time.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">But as I'm grabbing that, let me see some of my other questions. I can flip through and you can take some 
time to look at these blueprints, but are there some details that this blueprint isn't telling us that you 
remember from spending time in the building? So if you want me to flip to a certain page, let me know.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Not really. You're aware that the faculty offices were upstairs and they were all along a corridor facing to 
the west of the building where the Eisner building is now. So Brasmer's office was up there, Elliot's office 
was up there, and Pam's office was up there. Paul didn't really have an office. He was just living off the 
stage and where the shop was, that's where you could find Paul. So I don't even remember him having an 
office up there, but all four faculty were up there. They were always available. You never felt like you 
had to make an appointment. It was all very casual. You could just knock on somebody's door, &quot;-do you 
have 10 minutes Bras? Do you have 10 minutes, Pam? Is this a bad time? You look like you're busy. I can 
come back.&quot; It was very, very open.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah. Did you have a faculty member that you found yourself talking to more as a mentor, as an advisor?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 10 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.
No. No, I didn't. Again, because we were a small number of students and the faculty was small, I just felt 
everybody was really available to me. I wasn't really under anybody's... I didn't really have one person 
that was an advocate or a promoter or I was very lucky. My freshman year I walked onto Campus 
Brasmer was going to do the first show. He had previously selected it. It was a Commedia dell'arte. It was 
&quot;The Servant of Two Masters&quot; by Goldoni. And I think anybody in his position would, he knew what 
talent he had on campus from sophomores through seniors, and he had pretty much precast it in his mind, 
I think.
(33:22):
And the woman that he was going to cast as the lead, Mimi Beck, who was incredibly talented, stunning, 
tall, Auburn-haired girl, and he wanted her for the lead for that is what I came to understand after the fact. 
And she was very active in sorority life, and she was going to be leading the sorority rush for Chi Omega 
that semester. So she did not turn out for tryouts. So Bras was missing his leading lady. And I walked 
onto campus and I was tall, and it was a breaches part. You know what a breaches part is? It's where for 
purpose of plot, for purposes of plot, the woman is disguised and is dressed like a man because she's 
passing herself up as her brother just to get the comedy going. And I was tall, and my height is all in my 
legs, and he gave me the breaches part.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">That's fantastic.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">And that just started me on my way and just dumb luck. Hello.
(34:47):
Of people thought that I was Brasmer's girl. That wasn't true. It was serendipity. Serendipity.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah. No, but that's an incredible, especially freshman year to do something like that. That's exciting.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">It was very exciting. And then my penance was that I had two seniors in the cast who, oh my God, they 
were so experienced and they could have eaten me for breakfast, but they were very nice to me.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah,</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">It was a learning curve. I'm telling you.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Oh yeah, I was a freshman. This sounds, sorry. This is your time. I want to hear your story. As a freshman 
past, we do the Reynolds Playwright Program every two years where we bring in someone like a 
playwright to work on new work with students. So big deal as a freshman, I was like, automatically, I'm 
not going to get that because that's something that other students will get. And I ended up getting cast as 
funnily enough, the mom of a junior and a senior, which as a freshman year, I was like, okay, I'll take, I 
feel so. But they were so experienced and I was deeply very, very like, oh, this is going to be horrifying. 
They're going to hate me. And they were already so nice about it, and they thought it was funny too, that a 
AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 11 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.
freshman was playing their mom. And I was luckily cast with a transfer sophomore who wasn't a theater 
student as my husband. And so we were both, we felt like newbies, but everyone else was super nice 
about it. So always grateful for the nice seniors and juniors.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Absolutely.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah. Okay. Going back to the faculty a little bit, if the answer is no, that's totally fine. Do you think you 
would remember roughly which office was which, if you looked at the blueprint, which one? I know I can 
find out which one Elliot Stout's was, because what Mark had when he became a faculty member,</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">My recollection is that Brasmer's was the one that was closest to the front of the building. And I think 
Elliot was in the middle, and I think Pam was down toward the rear of the building. But I wouldn't put my 
firstborn's life on that premise.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Could you tell me a little bit about the personalities, a little bit of the professors, or was there, did certain 
students gravitate to certain kinds of work from other professors? A difference between doing a Brasmer 
show or a Stout show? Was there a perceivable difference? I mean, yes, because other people</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">I mean, certainly. They were certainly all very distinctive personalities. I don't remember Pam Hoffman 
ever directing a main stage play. I could be wrong about that, but I think that's right. I think if somebody 
checked the records, they would find that would be true. Paul Hoffman, to my knowledge and memory, 
only directed &quot;Dream Play.&quot; So other than that, it was brass or Elliot or student productions. We had more 
student productions. All you had to do was go to a faculty member and say, for instance, remember this is 
like '67 or '68, Carolyn Clay, myself and Barbara Mon, and Barbara did a lot of being the stage director in 
a lot of shows, very organized, kept everybody focused. She was great, and we were roommates, and we 
went to Pam Hoffman and we said, we have an idea, '67, we'd like to do this play called &quot;The Killing of 
Sister George.&quot; And it's a love triangle amongst lesbians. &quot;Fine. Talk to Paul about the sex, talk to Tom 
about the lighting and ask Lynn about costumes. And if you hit any bumps in the road, come and talk to 
me and my door's always open to you.&quot; This is pretty radical stuff in '67, '68, right?-
(39:24):
And they just made it easy for you. All of the building blocks were given to you, and you just went and 
you ran with the permission and make sure you weren't trying to use part of the facility when somebody 
else who had priority was scheduled. And we had that show ran on the main stage. They made room for 
us, and it was a learning experience. It was a three person play. All three of us acted in it, directed it, 
directed each other, and produced.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Oh my God, that's incredible. That's really, and this was 1967, so you were a sophomore?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">It was '67 or '68. You can see it in my Yeah. Thing that I gave you.
AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 12 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Wow.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">I know.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">That's really, one to have the inspiration going, I just want to do this with, and these were your 
roommates, right? Were they your roommates all four years or was this like,</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">No, no. There was one year when all three of us lived together, or maybe two years when we all see, one 
of the great things that happened for us, and this is a segue, sorry about that, but freshman year, what you 
now call the East Side campus, I think, which is where Huffman, where Liz and Crawford, that was all 
just women's living. That was all just women's dorms. And so for theater majors and music majors and art 
majors, dance majors, that was a pain in the neck to go up after go uphill to that quad, getting out of 
rehearsal at 12:30 in the morning. And then King Hall, where King Hall is on the lower campus?</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah, yeah.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">That was opened up as a woman's dorm, and we all got word of it sort of early on, and we all moved 
down to King Hall, and we lived there sophomore, junior, and senior years. And it was best thing ever 
because of proximity, number one, and number two, we were kind of off the grid and attention of the 
university officials. No, not in a bad way, but in just liberating way. We never took advantage of it, but it 
just gave us a lot of autonomy and it was great. And you could walk from the theater in a straight line on 
flat ground when you were pooped after a long rehearsal session or a performance. It was wonderful.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">I've been very jealous of-</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Was thought, I don't think maybe there were 12 rooms in it, so maybe 24 young women in there. So it 
was a very intimate living space for the people who live there.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">It sounds like a great opportunity to feel a little bit more independent and have a really good grasp on 
your space.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">And I raise it because we lived there together, and so a lot of the ideas that we germinated came out of our 
common living experience as well.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 13 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.
Yeah, no, that's something that's featured actually important in the play that I wrote is Hal wrote about 
how he just called it &quot;raking over the coals&quot; with Ace in their dorms and just thinking about what they 
wanted to do, new projects. Yeah, it's a huge part of, I feel like half of my theatrical instincts have come 
from late-night conversations in dorms after rehearsals, or not even in class or something, but just later 
being like, we could do something like this. And that's how most of 'em have happened.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">But to answer your question about how the different faculty handled things,
(43:31):
The light bulb went on for me pretty early, probably after working for Brasmer on &quot;Servant&quot; that I needed 
to be involved with as many shows as I possibly could be, even if there was not a quote role for me. So I 
went out for a lot of shows where I was just going to be part of the window dressing. &quot;Measure for 
Measure.&quot; I can't say the Shakespearean language to save my life. The words just do not come trippingly 
off the tongue. I don't know. &quot;Oh Dad, Poor Dad, Mamma's Hung You in the Closet and I'm Feelin' So 
Sad.&quot; No role for me, I was in a Conga line as a dancer. In &quot;Measure For Measure&quot; I was baud in the 
whorehouse. I was just window dressing, and I was just standing there as the wife of the Insane Asylum 
owner just watching the inmates. And I did that because I wanted to see the styles of different directors, 
and I wanted to see what the different actors brought in rehearsals that had meaty parts. And I viewed it 
all as a learning experience, and boy was it ever. And the fact that I had no lines didn't bother me at all. I 
was participating and I was learning, and I was growing, and I was building my instinct base, not just for 
theater. I ended up not staying in theater. I ended up becoming a lawyer, but the instincts that I came to 
rely on have stood me in good stead my whole life.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah, no, the rehearsal room is a really precious, powerful thing, and being in it, that instinct to just be a 
part of it, I think is wonderful.
(45:42):
And so in that context, I will say that I saw Paul Hoffman direct. I saw Elliot direct, I saw Brasmer direct. 
Brasmer was on a sabbatical my senior year in exchange. Went to London and a fellow who was a 
London Theater University guy came over and he directed &quot;The Recruiting Officer,&quot; the restoration 
comedy by Farquhar. And so I had his direction, and then Pat Ryan came in our junior year, or our senior 
year, she directed &quot;Three Sisters.&quot; So I saw a lot of different directors do their thing and much to the value 
of my education.
(46:42):
I think seeing just how definite rehearsal space can be run and different artistic opinion is, I think it's good 
not to get comfortable with just a certain way of doing things, and especially just having that confidence 
to keep working. Yeah. No, you've answered a lot of my questions. Essentially, the reason I ground it in 
the building so much is just so I can, for people who, I mean for everyone, my generation, we had no 
experience with this building. We never saw it, but I heard so many things about it. And so it always just 
fascinated me that it was just something that was there. It's just gone now.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">But there was</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Like people,
  </interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Yeah, the place that the audience would gather before a show and also go to for an intermission, and there 
was a word for it, and I'm not coming up with it. And it was right next,</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">The Foyer?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Yeah, the foyer worked out on the stage, the main stage. Then a group of actors in a smaller part of the 
bigger scene would go and work in the foyer. I remember in &quot;Flea in her Ear,&quot; Doug Condit and I had a 
scene, and plot wise, I played the wife of the lead, and she suspected her husband of not being faithful to 
her. And so this guy who had designs on her took her to a whorehouse to see if he was there with the 
intention of actually crossing the line with her.
And the scene was all about the French forest was all about the timing of slamming doors and stuff. And 
Elliot had his hands full with all of that going on. And he just said to Doug and I, &quot;go out to the foyer and 
just work out your piece of it.&quot; And we did, and we came back and it turned into one of the two bafo 
moments in the show, and it was more fun than I can tell you. So you'd have that autonomy as actors and 
the building lent itself to that is what I'm saying.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah. So those little B sides that you can run by yourself, it's fun to know there's a part of a show that you 
kind of helped direct and design. That was fine. That was ours. That's awesome.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Yeah,</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">We do that quite it too.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">And we came back and we did it for Elliot, and he was just like, &quot;keep it.&quot; Again, not really patting you 
on the back. And then we built it into a Bafo moment where it's a three-part time thing. It's between me, 
Doug, and the audience. And you can hold the audience's laughter and build it and then let it go down and 
then build it up again. It's better than sex. Better than sex. Incredible.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yes. No, that feeling is incredible. Yeah, I would have to agree. I'm so sorry. Could you explain Bafo 
moment? I don't know if I know that phrase.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">A bafo moment is when the audience is laughing so uncontrollably that it doesn't stop. They don't stop. 
And then when you are an actor on the stage and you're holding them, you can build the laughter even 
higher and elongate the period of laughter. Or you can let it die because somebody needs to come on and 
do something else. You can play with the audience. It's a three-way relationship between the two actors 
on stage in this case and the audience. And it is beyond heady. It's something to experience. It really is.
AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 15 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">No, yeah, those are incredible moments that you do not want to let go of.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Never.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">I was just talking, we had a new actor. There's a student named Henry Bailey who just started acting. He's 
a junior, but he's a creative writing major, but I think he's gotten fully hooked and wants to do acting now, 
but before a run of &quot;Tartuffe,&quot; he's like, &quot;I'm always really scared for this. But then my friend reminded 
me that this is the best scared feeling you could have because you're safe, but you're about to do 
something really cool.&quot; That kind of anticipation before going on stage.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">You have to have that. I remember being, I played Olga, the old maid sister in &quot;Three Sisters,&quot; she's the 
oldest of the three sisters, and Olga has the opening line in the closing line of the play. Thank you Mr. 
Chekhov. I was standing offstage waiting to go on and be the first actor to speak. And needless to say, the 
nervousness is building and building and building, and your stomach is kind of at your knees. And if you 
don't have that, then you don't have, in my experience, then you don't have that edge that you need to go 
out and carry you. You can't just walk on without, it's not paralyzing stage fright. I mean, I understand 
what that, I've never experienced it, but I can understand what that might be. But this is, it gets you on 
your toes.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah, no, it's an incredible feeling. Yeah. So frankly, you've, it's questions I haven't asked. You've already 
answered just by some of your stories.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">One of the things that I did, Nora, when I was out at Arts Remix is I did a small program and it was about 
lessons that I learned. And what I'll do is I'll just send you that and see if it sparks anything for you when 
you useful that I learned as a theater major that actually were useful as a lawyer and in my family life and 
my community life and whatever. And there may be some anecdotes in there that are helpful for you too. 
We'll see. If not useful for you, just ignore it. Okay.
(53:19):
No, I appreciate it already. There's several things I want to already link the foyer and I some the other 
things. So already this has been a great conversation. I'm just going to make sure, the
(53:34):
Thing that I'll say about Ace Morgan is that it always to me had a very warm, friendly, approachable, 
comfortable feeling to it. And maybe it's just the emotions that I carried after being so intimately involved 
there for four years, but I just always looked forward to coming in the doors, always did, and the building 
itself with no great shakes. But on the other hand, it was very utilitarian and we always found a way to 
make it work. I loved the building, loved it. And I think you will find to too, and I'm sure if you talk to 
others either earlier or after or during our time, I'm sure they'll echo that.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 16 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.
Yeah, no, every time I've asked someone about it, the amount of love that comes out when they describe 
it, it sounds like it was an incredible space that you all shared. So it is really meaningful to me that I get to 
collect some of these stories. It really does. Good. Yeah. It makes me happy to know that there's people 
who still hold onto these kind of things. Yeah. I guess my last question, just to round everything off is if 
there's something that we didn't talk about that you were like, this needs to be part of something that more 
people know about this building or some of your time there. Is there anything you would like to share?</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">No, really, really, really just that and technologically, I mean, I understand why it was at the end of its life 
and it was a challenge probably the last few years. It had to be used, but mostly during its tenure. It served 
its purpose very, very well. And the other thing I'll say, which is sort of the gist of what we said to Julie 
and your department chair and to you by way of copying you is Tom and I would love to see your project 
on Ace Morgan. Maybe reach out to and involve alums that maybe haven't been involved or bring back 
those that have been, but maybe haven't recently been. And maybe have a theater arts reunion either 
broken down into certain years or overall. I think that would be great. And I think it would be great for 
the university as well. And Tom and I are very excited about that as a possibility.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">Yeah, I definitely, I'm very, very open to that and would love to make that happen. I think knowing the 
scope of the rest of my senior year, I definitely want to include your and Tom's and a couple others I can 
gather from some of the people I've already been talking to. So I think essentially what I'm seeing, what I 
turn in as a senior is the tester for this being a bigger project is what I'm saying. So I have to finish out 
this research and also direct my own show and graduate
(56:43):
What are you directing?
(56:45):
It's an original work about Ace and Hal Halbrook. So it's called &quot;about my Friend where the parking lot 
play.&quot; And it's essentially all the stories, not about the building, but kind of book bookending, the 
building's history where it's about Hal Holbrook and Ace Morgan, and a student named Carol Jacquet, 
who also did shows with them. It's scenes from their time at Denison and also scenes with me and two of 
my friends who have since graduated. So it's essentially, I mean, it's probably a little sappy. It's my first 
attempt at full on playwriting.
(57:22):
That sounds very cool. Very cool.
(57:24):
Yeah, it's a dedication to theater students figuring themselves out. So we performed that in late April and 
we just started audition. We just started rehearsals. I auditioned a while ago.
(57:37):
Good luck with that.
(57:37):
Definitely. Thank you. Thank you. It is daunting, but it's fun. It's already very interesting. But yeah,</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">I will, my husband and I are rewatching &quot;West Wing&quot; and Hal Holbrook was a part of that ensemble. And
AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 17 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com
This transcript was exported on Apr 07, 2025 - view latest version here.
Speaker 3 (57:57):
Yeah, I'm a &quot;West Wing&quot; fan, so I'm definitely going to revisit some of his episodes. The student who's 
playing Hal Holbrook didn't know about him before, but I gave him a copy of his memoir and he has 
already texted me saying that he's halfway through, which I did not expect. So he's very eager, which is 
really helpful. But yeah, so thank you so much for this conversation. I will be sending you updates with 
this project. I'll obviously send the full project when it's fully up and I'll be reaching out to Tom really 
soon.</interviewee>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">If you find you hit a snag or you find that, I wish I'd asked her something, don't hesitate to be in touch, not 
to intrude on your time, which I understand you're under a lot of time pressure, but if I can be of help, let 
me know. Okay.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">I greatly appreciate it and thank you so much for your enthusiasm for this project. It was really lovely 
meeting you at Arts Remix. I'm glad that worked out.</interviewer>
  <interviewee n="Barbara">Nice to meet you too. It was a pleasure meeting the students. It really was. And to realize how smart 
everybody is and how committed you are and informed and not everything makes you hopeful when you 
wake up these days. And that was really made me feel very hopeful. So that was nice.</interviewee>
  <interviewer n="Nora">It was the same for us. It was lovely meeting all of you and seeing just how welcoming and excited and 
curious everyone is at whatever point. So thank you. Okay, so I make sure the technology goes right. I'm 
going to stop recording and make sure it saves. I'm going to stop sharing as well. And then recording.
AUDIO_Barbara_Williams_-70_3_21_Interview (Completed  03/24/25) Page 18 of 18
Transcript by Rev.com</interviewer>
</interview>
