<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<interview>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom"> Okay. My name's <persName xml:id="Person_207">Tom Berger</persName>, that's B-E-R-G-E-R. I
    entered Denison in 1966, graduated 1970. I was a theater arts major. I have a Bachelor of Fine
    Arts as opposed to a ba, several. I think Barbara actually had a BA and my focus, I don't think
    we really defined it. I can't recall how it was defined, but my focus was really all on the
    technical side, both design lighting, set design, technical stage management, all of that good
    stuff like that. So I don't think I stepped on the boards once in my four years there. Don't
    recall.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora"> Yeah, impressive streak. Amazing. My boss is a alum and
    he regretfully, he was almost able to get through his four years without performing anything.
    But then as a stage manager, I had fill in for a bit part and he was so close.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom"> I did some in high school and I left that behind me and
    after graduation, so anyway.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora"> Is that how you got interested into technical theater
    though? Was that your introduction?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom"> 
    Yeah, I guess so. I grew up in Berea, Ohio, which is up
    near Cleveland. It's the home of Baldwin Wallace College, another school, it was a Methodist
    college where Denison was of religious affiliated small schools in Ohio, and my sister was
    fairly active in the theater there especially. They had a summer theater program at BW as well.
    And so I guess that was my first exposure and I did some acting there, but I don't know, I just
    found it, I guess I was a little more comfortable in the back and I enjoy building stuff to an
    extent. So I think that became a more logical fit for me, and that's the direction it
    took.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">
    Nice to hear. Great. So if you could describe how much
    time do you think you spent during your dancing career? If you could guess how long you spent in
    the theater arts building? Could you quantify that?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">
    Well, actually it's interesting because I actually had,
    I'll use the term work study. I don't know what it was in my day, what the term was. So I
    actually had, I worked formal hours and was paid probably minimum wage in those days if that
    would've put me in the theater more hours. And I can't give you what the requirement was on
    that, but a lot, there's probably the only way to describe it in that regard. I am not even sure
    I could stab at a percentage of time between, are you talking about beyond classes in that
    sense?</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">(Completed 04/10/25) Page 2 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here. Any and all? I know that it's functioned as a classroom space,
    but also if you were a student worker. For me, I'm an Eisner Center Gremlin. I am here for work
    and for class and for performance.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">That was the same for us as A BFA. I had a higher
    concentration of hours for my degree in the theater. So in that sense, that probably put more
    time down there. And then just as you described, designing, building, running. I did a lot of
    stage management, tech management over the years, so I was there for a lot. Obviously a lot of
    performances over time, and this is, you'll have to take this out of your recording, the
    following, I actually lived in the theater for a semester, had to do with just my circumstances
    where I had been living. I've been living off campus with another guy and couldn't keep that
    going. So it's kind of a short notes thing. So : I literally was, as people described it, the
    ghost of the theater. And I don't know that anybody knows the true story behind
    that.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Wow. Out of respect, I will take that other recording,
    but I'm deeply interested to hear about, did you sleep in the green room? Where were
    you</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Down in one of the storage rooms off the green
    room.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Wow. Oh my God. Okay. Sorry, I'm taking aback with that
    a little bit. That's incredible. I didn't know. Now Dennison is completely all we had to live on
    campus, so was it common to be off campus living?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">It wasn't common to be off campus when I was there, the
    Greek system, the fraternities and sororities were very dominant. 90% of kids belong to them.
    There's a building behind Smith and Curtis. It's before you get down to kind of the newer
    dormitories there. I don't know what it is now. It was what was called the American Commons
    Club, a CC, and it was a non-Greek fraternity in a sense, and a number of guys belonged to that.
    I did not belong to a theater. We were referenced as gdi, goddamn independence, and the
    dormitories there were far fewer. I mean, if you belong to a fraternity, you live there after
    your freshman year, pretty much. I think they all had residence, so the college did not have,
    didn't have to provide a lot for the men. The women's fraternity sororities were not residential
    and you couldn't live off, I think we had to be juniors to live off campus. And of course, I
    mean there was a cost factor in doing that, and if you chose to do it, there might've been other
    restrictions on it, and there weren't a lot of us that did it, but it was something that it was
    allowed and was done.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah, it's interesting. The Greek life system is very,
    very different now on campus, not it's residential, but actually the reason I know about the
    American Commons Club is because part of this research has been about before the theater arts
    building existed, specifically with the history of Ace Morgan as a student, and Hal Halbert was
    an American Commons Club member for a bit. I think he dropped it after freshman
    year.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">(Completed 04/10/25) Page 3 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here. Who was that? I'm sorry? Hal Holbrook. Oh yeah.
    Yep.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah, because the content of my play, actually, Hal and
    Ace are characters, so I did a lot of research on what they were up to on campus, but okay, I
    will not include that on the audio if you so choose. Lemme know if you change your mind because
    a crazy, and I don't think they can get you in trouble, but understand</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">You could do it anonymously. Okay,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Okay.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">At this point. At this point, it doesn't really matter
    for me.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah, I don't think Adam Weinberg is going to be
    emailing you anytime soon.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">When I met him at, when I met with him at R three mix, I
    didn't tell 'em though.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah, okay. Oh, no, no. You were at Arts Remix. I'm
    sorry I didn't meet you in person. I was splitting my time, unfortunately. But no, I'm sure.
    Getting back to, yeah, it's hard to possibly even think to quantify the percentage of time spent
    in a Morgan, but if you were to describe maybe a typical day or what a schedule looked like for
    the different ways you were down there, so you said you were a student worker, was a student
    recent work study, so was it like you would go not for classes and work after?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah, I think generally it was probably late afternoon or
    afternoon, three to five, four to six, stuff like that. The intensity went up, not for the paid
    work, but the time intensity went up, obviously with a production. And when we got into
    rehearsal, whereas somebody like Barbara who would be in the show and was rehearsing and
    blocking and doing all of that, I and others were building in some cases, I mean, we had to do
    design projects as part of our senior project, but during the course of the rest of the time,
    usually the designs and well, for student productions, we did the design, set design, lighting,
    design for the major productions. Those were done by the faculty, at least the set design. And
    then our responsibility, my responsibility amongst others was to execute. And that could go, I
    mean, I know in some shows I remember working, you work till 12 at night and one o'clock in the
    morning just to finish off something in a particular element, we did a production of roa and the
    faculty member, whose name I can't remember, he was only there for a year, did the design and
    the backgrounding of it was sort of as if it was in a cave or a large cave. : We used cardboard,
    large piece of cardboard that were folded and meshed together. : (Completed 04/10/25) Page 4 of
    22 4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr
    14, 2025 - view latest version here. Not like a Rubik's cube, but they were a jigsaw puzzle, but
    they all had to be painted in a, he had a way that he wanted it done. And I did all of that, and
    I got about two thirds of the way through and I said, I got to, this was over a week's worth of
    time. I said, can somebody else sort of pick up on this? And he said, I'd love to accept that
    you've got a pattern now, and if we use somebody else, it would look different. But those were,
    you're getting ready for a show and everything we did had to be ready on for dress and final
    dress and opening night. And by what you're doing, you understand that whatever hours it took,
    basically,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Essentially nine to five is the main stage musical going
    on this weekend. And oh boy, the push for the set and the light, the sound. I think we're at a
    point now where it's the eye of the storm, but last week was a crunch week for sure. I'm
    actually going to share my screen real quick because what I have here is blueprints or the
    design blueprints of the building. So it might be a little inaccurate to what you actually
    experienced, but Okay. And I can make it bigger. Can you see, right now it should be the ground
    floor plan.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Oh yeah. There we go. Yes, I can.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Great. Here. So in terms of, yeah, here, I can make this
    a little, tell me if you want bigger or smaller, because right now I can, : It's : Being a
    little bit testy.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">You froze up. You froze up on me, Nora, so I missed any
    commentary</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">There. Shoot, can you hear me now</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Again?</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Hi, can you hear me? Yeah. Okay. Yep,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">I can hear you. Oh,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Shoot. I hope to : Let me know if there screen Yes. One
    second. (Completed 04/10/25) 4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Page 5 of 22 Transcript by
    Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14, 2025 - view latest version here.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah, all of a sudden, over the last minute or so you've
    been cutting out.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Oh, yikes. Oh, now we're fully frozen, aren't
    we?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">I don't, no, : You're okay now.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Okay. I'm hoping I saw it freeze up a little bit. I'm
    hoping we're okay now. Is this bigger for your view? Can you see</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">I'm frozen. Yeah, I can see it as large as you can make
    it helps, but that I can see it.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Okay, great. Hopefully I might need to stop sharing soon
    if that's what's sizing off the internet. But in terms of your experience as a student worker,
    how specialized was that work team? Were you doing all set light sound as a team or were more,
    was there smaller individual teams for, you're in the scene shop, you're on lighting or
    sound</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Would depend on the show? We typically, yeah. Yeah, sound
    was probably in most cases as far as work time was concerned, lighting was a major element
    because of the nature of the building. And one of the things that I think if you asked anybody,
    I don't know if I shouldn't say that, but one of the things that I loved about the building, and
    one of the great challenges for what I did was it was really a big black box so we could do
    anything and presentations were done all over in that regard. Number of the student plays we did
    in what they label here as the arena. That's where we did ROA three Sisters, which was my senior
    project for design and lighting was done on the main stage in front of the work, what they call
    the workshop there. So that was one of the most enjoyable elements of it, and a big challenge
    from a show running standpoint. : In many cases, there was not a lot as much as we could, I
    guess I would say. We didn't want to do a lot of set changes, a lot of moving of scenery and
    stuff like that. There wasn't really room for that. I mean, there was some that you could do,
    and we did, I think it was for Barbara's senior project, and we did it in rep, and the design
    was, as I recall, they were interiors, and we made a few changes swapped around, so the look was
    totally different. We could flip some sets and do stuff like that, but in general, they tended
    to be, I don't want, that's a tough way, but they were fixed sets to a certain extent, to
    minimize, because we just didn't have the capacity to move a lot of stuff, and we had no fly
    space at all. So you have turned off your microphone. I don't know if you did that on purpose
    or</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">(Completed 04/10/25) Page 6 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here. Only because I'm in a music practice room and someone is
    playing amazing sax over there, and I just want to not get that on the audio as much as
    possible. I am hearing and reacting.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">It is funny because this is the main floor, I believe,
    and for example, the shop. Then do you have a plan for the ground floor, which would include the
    green room, et</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Cetera? Yes, I do. Hold on. That's the first. Okay. This
    is one moment. Oh, please don't seize up. Nope.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Okay.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Those are other. Okay. I should have also a basement
    level I'm looking for. Yeah, this is,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Oh, there we go.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah, that's the basement level. Alright, fine.
    Yeah,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah, I was about to ask question.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Okay.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">With</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">The,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Oh, shoot. : Oh, okay. If you're frozen or thinking,
    we're back. Sorry, I'm back. As long as we're not frozen. What were you about to say
    though?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">(Completed 04/10/25) Page 7 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here. I'm looking at in the rehearsal room, trap door above, and I
    don't recall that, actually.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">I'm going to guess that was aspirational on the
    architect's part. It's good to know that that might happened. Yeah,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Because not even sure the small one in the storage area
    existed. I could be wrong about that, but I'm drawing, drawing a blank.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Good to know. I'm going to make a note</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Of that.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">I'll check with some others.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">And our primary storage, as far as theater was concerned
    was to the left here off the rehearsal room, this smaller storage area on each side of the
    rehearsal room, and then the big storage area and back. I don't recall using the storage room
    upfront that much. I think that if anything, that might've been a, I'm thinking of more
    administrative stuff, faculty stuff and things like that, which I mean, it would've been theater
    related, but it was not props and the like, but I can't remember that one. And the one I think
    off to the side on the lower part of your graph here, storage. I think that was, no, I think
    costumes were upstairs. Costumes were upstairs, but I could be,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">I was asking Barbara A. Little bit. I know she was
    definitely much a performer director, but her friend Lynn was a costume person, and I asked
    about where costuming specialized, and I heard more about her working in the women's dressing
    room. But if I can switch in between the scans, if you think, but more importantly for you as
    you as a student worker, what were the, I'm assuming the workshop was a place you would be
    regularly working in and then also in the actual theater, but where were your normal
    hunts?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah, no, that was it. We used the storage rooms on the
    main, the basement level, if you want to call it that. We had lighting. The ones that were down
    there were said switchboard room, and Yeah, there you go. The transformer room, those two rooms
    we used were stored down there. The transformer room was : The lighting control : System. It was
    very strange. It was driven by vacuum tubes, which you might not even know what that is. Nora
    Cashman : (Completed 04/10/25) Page 8 of 22 4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by
    Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14, 2025 - view latest version here. I'll say
    preamp. I can imagine</interviewee>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Predating transistors. Okay. You had tubes that provided
    for anything electronic. They were how you would control if you had a high fi set. Okay. Stereo
    set. I know you're not even understanding those things. They would have tubes in them, and those
    were the transistors of the day. Our lighting system was all tubes and it was very finicky. I
    think, as I recall, we were one of just a few in the whole country that still had that system. I
    had come off, I went to a prep school and our theater, which had been built in 58, 59, 19 58,
    59, I, all of the lighting controls were mechanical. I mean, they were really, that was still a
    standard that you would use in that. And when we came to this and going, oh, electronic, this
    ought to be great. Well, it had its issues. So that was all down. I spent probably too much time
    down there trying to make sure it kept working at the time, but that was downstairs more for
    anything related to that or moving stuff upstairs. But yeah, most of my work time was in the
    shop.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Can you describe some of that? What was the workshop
    environment looking like? I know we have just like it's this big, you've</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Got a fabulous, you got a fabulous shop.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yes.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">I walked into it. We got a tour, fortunately, and when
    you walked in on our shop, it was almost exactly the same. You walked through there. There was a
    huge overhead door between the main stage, the platform, they call it there and the shop. And on
    the side, you walked in off the main stage to the right was a table saw exactly the same as when
    you walk into the Eisner. The layout was exactly the same except the Eisner. You had probably
    twice as much depth to your workshop that we had and the shop for major stuff. That was also our
    only storage area. So we built stuff and stored it there, and we also did all of our painting in
    the shop. Well, almost all of it's something we would do right on stage if we had to. That
    generally was done on your drawing here, down at the lower end where the load, what's the
    loading dock, basically? So that was the paint room. I mean, it was not really a room, but
    that's where we did that kind of work. And we did have some stuff up in the rafters. We could
    put some stuff up top, but again, not a lot of storage area. When push came to shove, I spent a
    lot of time in the tech director's office. That was me when I was there.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">What was that space for? Specifically?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Anything and everything. It was used as a dressing room
    as need be, and we store small props in there, and it wasn't, I had a desk and trying to
    remember what else it was. It was very basic. Okay. We're not talking anything exotic
    here,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora"> But very practical and functional. That's what I've heard from
    Barbara is you had to be pretty creative with how you're using your space.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah, I mean, everything was, I mean, because it was
    limited to begin with. You were creative in what you built. You were creative, what you kept and
    the like. And then it became, what do I want to say? Exacerbated, I guess is the best word,
    depending on where the show was physically in the building. Like I say, some stuff was on the
    main stage, some was done in the arena, and when you change that, you might lose storage space
    or the like is bras once said that, what do you use that big rolling door for? And I was just
    new. I was a freshman. I said, oh, move sets in and out. And he said, well, you could use it for
    the gates of hell too. And in essence, that's what he did when we did marad production, not as
    the gates of hell, but gates into the asylum.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Wow.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">So you could extend,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">There's production photos of that that I've seen with
    the cast stage.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">You say you have seen photos. I think</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Barbara sent me something.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah, yeah, she probably did. We were looking at some
    photos that she had with her, and we were looking at it and I said, the thing I remember about
    it was she was knitting a scarf and it just got bigger and bigger and bigger. She kept knitting
    it throughout the whole production.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Even just a blanket. Yeah.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yes, exactly.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">That's</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">A</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Pretty ingenious space though.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">It is. Oh, one of the other, an example also of how it
    could be done. I mean, bra directed Marad, there was a platform that extended out, it was up in
    the air, probably seven or eight feet off the stage level, and it was a couple feet wide, and it
    extended out into the arena through the proscenium and out into the arena, and it was used as
    part of the performance of the production.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">That's incredible. That would be cool to see. Yeah.
    Barbara spoke really highly of using the arena as a space with more untraditional seating or in
    the round. Going back to, you said three sisters was your senior design project. Did you design
    set light? What was that?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Design? Yeah, set and lining both.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Good for you. That's pretty extensive. So yeah, I guess
    going back to maybe some of your, going through the years at Denison, what was your arc through
    being a student worker with your BFA? Did you specialize at one point or what were you finding
    yourself drawn to more? Who were you working with</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Outside of the theater or just in general?</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">It can be in general, but if, okay, sorry. Let me be
    more specific. With the team that you worked with as a student worker versus how you ended up
    doing that senior design project, did you just start as a student worker and then you decided
    this is what you wanted to, did you go in knowing you were going to do A, B, F, A, for
    example?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">No, not initially. We had a pretty highly defined, I'll
    call it, highly defined. I can't make the comparison. I don't know what the curriculum structure
    is today, but we had a number of courses and requirements that we had to take in freshman year,
    starting with good old Western civilization, two semesters of that. But we had a requirement, we
    had a language requirement, we had a science requirement. What else? We had language science. We
    had an English requirement. So initially I wasn't said, oh yeah, this is what I'm going to do
    for four years and when I graduate, here's where I'm going to go. I think though, as I worked
    through freshman year and putting all the requirements behind me and said, yeah, I think the
    theater A, the theater is what I want to major in the BFA. I think that early on I was thinking
    that I would graduate and ultimately get a master's and probably come go on to teach in a
    college or university. That was my thinking. But that changed as it got closer to graduation,
    and we were dealing with, our disruption at the time was the Vietnam War, and so those of us
    graduated, especially 19 69, 19 70, 71 was very disrupted for a lot of us, not for everybody,
    obviously, but for a lot of us it was. So that changed my, my course of thinking as I got closer
    to graduation.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Did you end up having to serve? (Completed 04/10/25)
    Page 11 of 22 4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was
    exported on Apr 14, 2025 - view latest version here.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">No, I did not. I believe it turned out we, in the fall of
    1969, the fall of my senior year, we had the first draft lottery, which the government had
    instituted. They were looking for a more fair distribution because what was happening there were
    different. Draft was madatory for all males, and there were deferments that were implemented
    during the 1960s to change, to try to recognize, okay, first deferments were college. So if you
    went to college that granted you a deferment, didn't get you out of it, but it deferred. And
    some of the thinking was, okay, if I do that, then the war won't be as bad. Then there were
    deferments for marriages if you were married, and this affected my older brother who was a 1962
    grad. He graduated 62. He had a college deferment. He got married right after graduation. It
    became, there was a marriage deferment, and then there was a deferment if he had children, and
    he kind of had that helped him or moved his situation along. : So he did not serve in Vietnam.
    Those who were in place, and then they were the draft, it was getting stratified, and so if you
    were lower economic status, it was a very good chance you were going to go because you weren't
    going to college and didn't have the other deferrals. In my, I think it was sophomore year,
    which would've been 67, 68, they instituted a draft test, something similar to a civil service
    exam, and they used that as another cutoff or deferment. So if you passed, you were fine. If you
    didn't, you were definitely draft eligible if not drafted. And then </interviewee> 
  <snippet n="1"> <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom"> In my senior year, in the
    fall of 69, they had the draft lottery, which was the intention was to sort of smooth it out,
    and I was, depending on how you look at it, for me, I was fortunate in that I had a very high
    draft number, and so if you were from one to about 125 or so was sort of you're going, and the
    next third was kind of up for grabs, and then my draft number was 351. So there was no chance
    that I would be, if I was drafted, then we had a real problem as a society. But that's a whole
    nother issue on that we were doing, we were in the theater the night of the draft because we
    were all trying to listen to it, and we were rehearsing, and I can't remember what the show was.
    I don't know if that was <production xml:id="Production_3">Three Sisters</production> or not,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">But this was your senior year, was it? Do you remember?
    It was the fall of the spring.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">The draft lottery was in the fall, and I can't remember,
    <production xml:id="Production_3">Three Sisters</production> was the fall show. It might've been.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Okay,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">You need to look that up. Let me</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Know. I'll cross reference this what I have. But you
    were in the theater when this was happening. Was this in the newspaper? How was this being
    shared?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">It was being broadcast on television and on the radio.
   </interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Oh, wow.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">And we had, somebody was monitoring it. We couldn't have
    it, obviously couldn't have it in the theater itself, so it was somebody's <cluster xml:id="Cluster_1">
      office</cluster> and people were going in and out and listening to it and tracking it as best they could.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">I can never imagine a more distracted</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">At the moment. It was pretty, it was.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah. That's really harrowing.</interviewer>
    <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">It is interesting. <persName xml:id="Person_200" n="Barbara">Barbara</persName> and I were talking about it
    and the pressures and the stress and all fell hardest on the guys because we were the ones going
    drafted. But it affected the women as well, not quite as directly, but it affected them
    nonetheless.</interviewee>
</snippet>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah. I can't imagine what that feeling is. I mean,
    doing my research about Ace and Hal in the forties and how Dennison's campus looked with lesson
    at the time they were going to school, it was already, people were either volunteering or going
    off, so there's just not many men on campus at all. So seeing the shows they chose, even they
    did letters to Lucerne, a mostly women cast, things like that. But I can't imagine what,
    especially to have something so life changing. You got to rethink your,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Well, there were people, there were guys that the next
    day they had left town, and as far as we know, they went to the destination was Canada, get out
    of the country and hide out. Then on top of all of that, 1970, in May of 70 was the shootings at
    Kent State. That just was one more thing that we didn't need. I don't know if Barbara had told
    you we did some outdoor theater moving around the campus, three or four of us, she and I, and a
    couple others as not a protest per se, but just sort of a statement on the issue of the war,
    highlighting the deaths, the impact that Vietnam and had on the United States since the fifties.
    People didn't realize that it started in the fifties, really, with US advisors to Vietnam, and
    anyway, that has little to do with Ace Morgan. Other,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">The context is really important. Fascinating. I mean,
    I'm going to get back to my questions, but also the other things I study in the archives is
    students, again, the blurry lines between protests and activism on campus, but specifically,
    I've been tracked, especially with now with different movements about us militarization, looking
    at the South African anti-apartheid movement in the eighties, but also looking at the Vietnam
    War protests in the sixties, and now with Palestine. There's just like the archived does a good
    job really documenting different ways students reacted. So Barbara didn't tell me about that.
    That's really incredible. </interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Well, I think that that was a case of yes, it affected
    her and the women, but not in the same way. So I mean, it's indelible to me. I mean, I'll
    digress for a second because my story is a little bit more unusual in that my birthday is April
    25th, and I was born very late at night, and my birth certificate said that I was born on the
    26th. The nurse just wrote the next day, and a friend of my father said, who was a lawyer and a
    judge. He said, you ought to get that fixed. You never know. That's 1948 when that happened. And
    so they did, and April 26th was two in the draft lottery. So had that never been changed, I
    would've gone. Oh</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">My God, that's incredible.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">I think the only difference between me and Barbara is
    just the impact that it directly had on us.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Absolutely.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">In that way. So not minimizing her by any
    stretch.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">No, no, no. Yeah, but don't worry about digressing. I'm
    trying to capture student's stories, so this is all extremely interesting, so don't worry about
    that to zero back in. So was it a similar crop of people always? Who were the people you worked
    with the most? Do you think there was a lot of tech actor interaction or</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Oh, yeah. Well, first of all, there were classes we all
    had to take in different aspects of the theater, everything, acting classes, costuming, makeup
    tech, lighting. I mean, everybody took at some basic level for that. And so there was a core, I
    mean, I think Barbara and I figured there were only four of us that were theater majors in our
    class, and so if you, and I can't remember everybody, but you extend that out. So at any given
    time, there were maybe 2015 or 20 theater majors. Now, there were a lot of folks that came down
    and did stuff. They might've had a requirement to do something in the arts and the rest, but the
    core folks were us. And it's interesting because when I think back, there was a lot of stuff I
    did on my own. Well, there was a faculty member who was a tech director. It was a taught tech
    and the like.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Was that Hoffman?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah, Paul Hoffman.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom"> Okay. And so he did stuff as well, but there was a lot of stuff
    that was just, Hey, you got to go do this, and so I went and did it. And it's interesting. I
    hadn't thought about that. I hadn't thought about who else was there working with me. I mean, I
    remember a guy, it was Jack Hoffman. He was a student a couple of years behind who did a lot of
    stuff in props and the</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Rest, no relation to</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Hoffman. Okay. So yeah, we're pretty, a pretty tight knit
    group or tight knit in the sense of, yeah, we were the ones that were always doing the work and
    everything else like that.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">It's a lot of forced proximity. You get to know people
    you want to or not when you do that work. Yeah,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah. Absolutely. Absolutely.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah. Okay. Maybe this is an unfair question, but if you
    had to choose a show that you look back on the most, your favorite or could be your least
    favorite, just memorable, what would be a show you would highlight?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Oh, wow. Well, certainly, I mean, for me, because of what
    I had to do as Project Three Sisters certainly stands out, and when I talk about senior project,
    we all had a senior project. We had to do something as part of our graduation requirement. One
    of my fond memories was actually not a show, but we hosted the Preservation Hall jazz band from
    New Orleans. They performed on our stage, so it was an intimate audience, great music. These
    guys were all 85 years old or older, and they were a stitch. One of the guys talking about one
    of his compatriots say, yeah, the doc had him in and said his heart wasn't so good, so he had to
    cut down to less than a pint a day of bourbon, things like that. And now that sticks in my mind,
    I think, because it was an outside show, and we probably did a few others over the course of the
    time, but I don't remember any of the others. But I do remember that one in a meaningful way,
    and Anda also was one that sticks with me again for the work and the design and what we
    ultimately wound up with in that And Three Sisters, : MARAD three Penny Opera.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">You did three Penny Opera?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">No, wait, did we do three Penny or did we do Mahoney? No,
    we did three. Penny.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">(Completed 04/10/25) Page 15 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here. We did that. I was in that two years ago. That's fun to hear
    about. Did you do crew for that? Where you stage managing? What was your Yeah, was</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Stage manager on that one. The other one that, it's
    funny, I sometimes forget about, but it was a small show, was waiting for Gau design. I did the
    set and lighting design for That's : Also did for Gado and for Three Sisters and several others.
    I did the photography as well. So you'll see some of my work in the archives.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah, I'm scheduled to go back and get some photos, so
    I'm definitely going to be looking for some of the stuff you're describing.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah, that's great. So Gado, that was fun. I mean, the
    sixties was a lot of avant garde theater work too. I mean, just in general, throughout the
    country and throughout Europe, especially</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">As a student, were you drawn to Avantgarde work or if
    you,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">I'm sorry. Choosing, I'm sorry, Nora, you broke up on
    that. What was the question?</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Do you think as a student, were you drawn to that kind
    of avantgarde guard work? Was that just the department atmosphere or taste?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Well, it was pretty much department atmosphere. There
    were elements of it that I found intriguing because I was also, we didn't have minors per se
    academically, but I had a focus, and I guess I probably had enough hours today that'd a minor in
    psychology. And as kind of to an aside of that, I had a strong interest in philosophy and the
    avant garde theater sort of lent itself to that. Not that a lot of it stuck with me in the years
    since then, but I found there was work that I found it interesting, some of it disturbing as a
    student trying to figure it out and the like, but it was, I think a general feeling throughout
    the department. I mean, the avant-garde was something that we worked with. It was
    current.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah. It's so fascinating to track the different, on a
    larger scale, theatrical trends, well, not even trends that might discredit what's happening,
    but what movements were going in and out with what the theater department is interested
    in.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Well, and then we were also,</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">(Completed 04/10/25) Page 16 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here. I realized</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">The film program was just starting when I, Elliot Stout
    was hired, Elliot was kind of focused in on that. Actually. I was involved with a couple other
    guys. We made a film on campus, was a daily life on campus, but it was focused on the minority,
    the small minorities. I mean, when I was there, I think we had six African-American students on
    the entire campus, and so that environment was totally different. I mean, Denison was a white
    campus. There was no question about</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">So we did a film on that, looking at that within the
    context of life, daily life at the school. So yeah.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Do you know what the archives has that that's an
    incredible piece of Denison history.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Oh, do I still have it?</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">It was done in something called Super
    eight.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Super eight, okay.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">The standard camera we could use was eight millimeter.
    That was low cost and stuff, and anybody could do super eight a bigger frame, so we had to go
    with that one for sure. One of our projects totally diverging. We were assigned, we had to do
    stage a play or an event or an activity in the theater somewhere. I did mine in the
    kitchen.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Oh my gosh. Wait, okay, hold on. You mean in the theater
    building?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">And people came up and made a sandwich and we hung out.
    Sorry, in the Ace Morgan in the kitchen. Ace Morgan. Yeah, right</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">(Completed 04/10/25) Page 17 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here. There. Oh my gosh. So right here. Okay. Your description of
    your piece cut off a little bit. Could you say it one more time? You said something about
    sandwiches.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Well, yeah, I made a quote into a deli, so provided
    mustard, mayonnaise, rye bread, all that and some cheeses and meats and everything, and people
    come in and interact. It was very free flowing. The one commentary I got was now it was okay
    from a faculty was, it was okay. It would've been better if you'd had a giant pickle walk in the
    middle of it. That's why I'm a tech guy. I am not a director, not a writer, not a
    producer.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">You would like my friend Lindsay, they're senior theater
    piece they did, they sat in a kitchen and the whole time it was like monologuing and other
    actors doing stuff, but they were baking brownies the entire time. By the end, they just cut 'em
    up and handed 'em to the audience, so it was in real time. They tested so many brownies on me
    too. I got really tired of 'em, just like, stop making me eat these.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">There were too many brownies. Take them down to a
    limit.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">No finding quick succession. There is a limit, but yeah,
    over a span, there's never a limit. No,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Exactly. Exactly.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah. Wow. I just want to be respectful of your time. It
    is 1 53.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">My time is open. I'm retired, so go have at
    it.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Great. Yeah. I guess you've answered most of my
    questions, which is great. Can I ask what you do? What happened after Denison? Did you pursue
    theater?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">No, I actually, I did for, is that right? I'm trying to
    think if it was before or after graduation. I worked as the tech director at the summer theater
    at Baldwin Wallace.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Got it.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">I wasn't, again, sort of coming off of Vietnam and
    everything else. I wasn't sure what I wanted to do realistically, and so I did that for the
    summer and did design set building the whole nine yards. Probably the most memorable piece that
    we did was cabaret and the guy that directed it was, we knew him as Mike (Completed 04/10/25)
    Page 18 of 22 4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was
    exported on Apr 14, 2025 - view latest version here. Telac. He was a graduate of, he was a
    classmate of mine in, we grew up together in Bea. He went to Carnegie Mellon, came out, he did
    this production of Cabaret. He went on, he was one of the two artistic guys on
    Godspell.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Oh, : Wow. That's incredible. : And he had changed his
    name at that point. He became John Vac, but he was Mike to me. But so I did that summer and then
    just wasn't fully directional. Worked with some buddies on some odd job work and stuff like
    that, and said, you know what? As a lot of a number of folks did, said, I'm going to Europe. I'm
    going to see what's going on, and packed my bags and hoofed it over to Europe and traveled
    around in Europe and landed a job when I was there. So worked in Europe for about almost a year
    in 1971 and worked for an American company corporation, and when the economy became a problem,
    they closed that office in Amsterdam and I came back and went to work for them in Boston. And
    while I was doing that, I guess I just sort of started seeing myself in a more, I'll use the
    word business environment. : I don't know if it was business per se, but working within an
    organization, I found that I had a propensity of some sort for analytical work, work, financial
    work analytics, and so I ultimately went back to school at Boston College and got an MBA in
    finance and strategic planning, and early part of my career after I graduated there was in
    corporate world, and I shifted into not-for-profit work along the way through different
    situations, and that was, I found that for me, very rewarding. I could do the financial work and
    if you want to call it the arts side or the softer side, I dunno what the right terminology is,
    and much of that was in arts organization. Much of my career was in arts organizations, museums,
    some higher education zoos, botanical gardens, and ultimately came full circle, I guess at the
    Adrian Arts Center for the Performing Arts in Miami. And my last job before I retired, I was
    there for 10 years as their vice president of finance and administration. : Wow.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">So I did theater in the end.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah. That's awesome. Yeah, it's been nice to hear where
    alumni have gone through. I know Barbara became a lawyer, and it all kind of makes sense what
    the things we found doing theater where they also apply elsewhere. It doesn't surprise me that
    you were good at analytical work as a tech person.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Well, yeah, because yeah, you have to solve a lot of
    different problems. What I found for myself in a career is as I, early on, as I took work within
    the not-for-profit and within the arts community, I found that I got a lot of satisfaction out
    of being involved with those organizations and primarily the educational work that they were
    doing with young people, and that, I think became that, if you want to say a defining aspect to
    the work that I did and my career. (Completed 04/10/25) Page 19 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah, that's great. Also, as someone who's a horrified
    senior trying to get a job, but also that's good to hear about. I'm applying to a lot of arts
    admin, donor relations jobs. Hopefully we'll get one. I'd just like to work. If I can work in an
    arts organization, I'd feel good.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Well, there certainly there's a need and who knows how
    disruptive it's going to be here in the next 3, 4, 5 years. But part of what I talked about at
    Arts Remix was in the eighties, I was working at the Museum of Science in Boston, and we were
    hosting a museum conference, and I looked at the agenda three or four days, people from all over
    the country and everything like that. I'm looking at this and going, there's nothing in here for
    finance and administrative people. The people on the planning committee were like, oh yeah,
    that's the way it is. I'm going, no, it isn't. I literally pick up the phone and started calling
    my cog and people I didn't know, but who did my job in other museums : Said, would you come, I'm
    going to host a luncheon. Would you come to Boston and we'll talk about whatever. 50 people
    shined up from around the country, and at about the same time, a guy who we became very good
    friends. He was my counterpart at the Field Museum of Natural History. He was having a similar
    conversation with the American Association of Museums. I was working with the Science museum
    community. He was working with the American Association, and we got, and then we started doing
    and created opportunities for that at the American Association of Museums. My commentary at
    Remix was there's a lot of stuff there that nobody knows about. Okay. You mentioned development
    and funding and all the rest of that. That's a reasonable and appropriate career path because if
    you have a bias to the arts and you're in an arts organization, you can sell that. Okay. In a
    manner. But there is a tremendous need for what I did. Financial people, administrative people,
    marketing people running volunteers, doing stuff like that, and you can still be plugged into
    the artistic side of the organization. There's nothing to prevent that. I had my financial team
    in Miami one, one of the accountants was a violinist. She played with a regional orchestra. Two
    of the folks were very active volunteering within the center itself with kids that we worked
    with it. There was a lot of arts in the staffing people doing that work, but they were better. I
    always said that they were better at their work by doing that because then they understood what
    the issues were on the other side, : And we worked very, very hard. I worked very hard
    throughout my career educating my arts counterparts, say, you need to understand what I do.
    Okay, because I can help you. I can help accomplish. I can get you resources. I can help you
    strategically and modify and the like. And that I would even up to the day, almost the day I
    retired, some people would look at me and go, why are you interested in that? I'm going, it's
    what we do. It's our mission. And more I know about the more I am intimately involved with the
    mission better I am at what I do as a financial and administrative guy.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah. Well, I think my last thing here is just
    essentially to hand over to you. Is there anything that we did not discuss about maybe your time
    at Denison or the theater arts building that you're like, I really wish this was documented, or
    you want to share with others if there's any last things you can think of? If not, those are
    my</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Questions. No, and it was fun running into Barbara at our
    remix. I mean, it was like we hadn't seen each other in 55 years and just started telling old
    stories and they hopping in the car, driving to New York City (Completed 04/10/25) Page 20 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here. because we didn't have any scotch coming back. That was me and
    Barbara and I forget who the third person was, or four of us, I think, and coming back and
    hitting route, coming off of the interstate and hitting Route 2 37 coming into grandville, and
    the theme for Mission Impossible comes on the radio, and we were like, that's it, man. No, that
    tells it all right there. No, I can't think of anything that would might be of value. I'll say
    that in a sense. But certainly you have more questions as you're working through your stuff.
    Don't hesitate at all to call or touch base. I'll be glad to be to share any absolutely. Any
    information, good, bad, or indifferent.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Thank you. Yeah, no, all is useful. Nothing is useless.
    This has been great. There's a lot of stuff that I didn't know about before. I've been trying to
    piece together what I know about this building with each new perspective, but really
    interesting. So I thank you so much again for taking the time. I'll be in touch if I have any
    other questions. Hell or high water, I'm going to have something by the end of the semester, so
    I will share what exists. Oh,</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah, no, whatever you have. Whatever you have will be. I
    don't know that I'll be on campus. It's interesting. I don't know. I'll be on campus before you
    graduate, but my wife's, one of her great nephews is actually a freshman. Oh, wow. In
    journalism. His name is Jack Quick. Jack Quick. We were able to see him when we were there for
    our three mix and all that. That's</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Awesome.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Sometime over the next five years. I know we'll be back,
    if not later.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">How do you spell the last name? Is it
    WICK?</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah. Q-U-I-C-K.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Q-U-I-C-K. Oh, okay. I know some journalism people I'll
    ask. That's awesome.</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">Yeah.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">If you are, please let me know. If it lines up, I might
    have tickets if you want to see the play that's based off of some of this work, but if not,
    totally fine. But I really appreciate it, and yeah, I will share what I have. I mean, I'm hoping
    for this to continue past graduation because frankly, I'm going to be an alumni and I still care
    about this program. So</interviewer>
  <interviewee xml:id="Person_207" n="Tom">(Completed 04/10/25) Page 21 of 22
    4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by Rev.com This transcript was exported on Apr 14,
    2025 - view latest version here. Good.</interviewee>
  <interviewer xml:id="Person_300" n="Nora">Yeah. But thank you so much. I'm going to stop recording
    now just so I make sure that's saves, and then I'm going to make sure it's all stop share and
    then stop. (Completed 04/10/25) Page 22 of 22 4_9_25_Tom_Berger_Interview_AUDIO Transcript by
    Rev.com</interviewer>
</interview>
